Guide to the Lois Stifel collection of tobacco ephemera, 1880-2019 and undated RL.11677
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
- Printed Materials, 1880-2019 and undated; 4
  - CDC (Centers for Disease Control and Prevention)--Smoking cessation posters, undated (Oversize-folder 1)
    Includes: The Benefits of Quitting; Within 20 Minutes of Quitting
  - Changing Times--Cigaret Ads: A Study in Irresponsibility, 1962 (Box 16)
  - Chesterfield--Luxury Merchandise catalogs, 1969-1975 (Box 16)
  - Chesterfield--Postcard, undated (Box 16)
  - Children's Cancer Classic souvenir programs, 1976-1978 (Box 16)
  - Cigarette Pack Collectors' Association correspondence, 2002 (Box 16)
  - Consumer Reports--Cigarettes on Trial: Tests and Testimony, 1957 (Box 16)
  - Consumer Reports--Special issue on cigarettes and smoking, 1960 (Box 16)
  - Consumer Reports--The Truth about True's (True Magazine) Article on Smoking, 1968 (Box 16)
  - Convenience Store/Outlet--Direct mail, 1997-2001 (Box 16)
  - Council for Tobacco Research USA report, 1990 (Box 16)
  - Crosby Golf Tournament booklet (RJR print advertisement), 1987 (Box 16)
  - David Brown--Old Joe and Mickey Nose to Nose (Joe Camel recognition among children), 1991 (Box 16)
  - Desmond Jenson--Racketeers at the Table, 2013 (Box 16)
  - Donald Cooley (True magazine)--Who Says Smoking Causes Lung Cancer?, 1954 (Box 16)
  - Doral--Direct mail, sweepstakes, 1998-2001 (Box 16)
  - Eclipse--E-mail promotion, 2003 (Box 16)
  - Eclipse--Website screen shot, 2016 (Box 16)
  - Elizabeth Franklin (Cosmopolitan)--Why Did They Name It Camel (with correspondence), 1960, 1996 (Box 16)
  - Emory Healthcare--Card announcing tobacco-free policy, 2001 (Box 16)
  - Florida Tobacco Control Clearninghouse--A Call to Action: The Truth About Big Tobacco's Counter-advertising Campaign, 2001 (Box 16)
  - Forbes--Tobacco: Embattled, Embittered and Uneasy, 1963 (Box 16)
  - George Waldron--From Sir Walter Raleigh to the Tobacco Trust, 1901 (Box 16)
  - Gerard Petrone--Tobacco Advertising: The Great Seduction, 1996 (Box 19)
  - Grim Reapers--Brochure, stickers, undated (Box 16)
  - Harvard Crimson--Article reprints (includes poem "My Cigarette" by Charles Fletcher Lummis), 1880-1964 (Box 16)
  - Helen Hill Miller--Tobacco and the Brilliant (ship), 1976 (Box 16)
  - IGA Grocergram--Includes advertising for Bucks (Philip Morris) and VQ (Forsyth/RJR), 1990 (Box 16)
  - James Shaw (Southeastern Antiquing and Collecting Magazine)--Exotic Cigarette Brands, 2004 (Box 16)
  - Jamestown-Yorktown Foundation--The Story of John Rolfe, 1962/1977 (Box 16)
  - Janet Pearce (Family Health magazine)--Is There a Plot to Keep You Smoking?, 1978 (Box 16)
  - Joe Queenan (American Spectator)--The Week of Smoking Dangerously, 1995 (Box 16)
  - John Fry (Ski magazine)--Smoke Screen (tobacco promotion of skiing events), 2009 (Box 16)
  - John Greenwald--Smoking Gun (on Liggett & Myers), 1997 (Box 16)
  - John Heller (U.S. News and World Report)--The Truth About Smoking and Cancer: What Is Known and Unknown, 1957 (Box 16)
  - Joy Krause (Milwaukee Journal Sentinel)--Where There's Smoke There's an Ashtray, and Someone Who's Eager to Collect It, 1997 (Oversize-folder 1)
  - Kent--Olympic Guide, 1960 (Box 16)
  - Kent--Pro Football Fact Finder, 1970 (Box 16)
  - Kwik Trip (Quiktrip)--Direct mail, 1997-2003 (Box 16)
  - L.L.Whiddon Speaks Out on Smoking and Coronaries, 1963 (Box 16)
  - Life Magazine bicentennial issue--Article on Raymond Loewy (Designer of Lucky Strike logo), 1976 (Box 21)
  - Liggett & Myers--Advertising Age profile, 2003 (Box 16)
  - Liggett & Myers--Catalog of Presents, 1917 (Box 16)
  - Liggett & Myers--Central Division souvenir, 1897 (Box 16)
  - Liggett & Myers--Chesterfield Cigarettes: A Camera Story, 1937 (Box 16)
  - Liggett & Myers--Chesterfield envelopes, 1976 (Box 16)
  - Liggett & Myers--Clippings, 1976 (Box 16)
  - Liggett & Myers--Daily memoranda book, 1929 (Box 16)
  - Liggett & Myers--Employee benefits brochure, undated (Box 17)
  - Liggett & Myers--For You: The Chesterfield Story, 1951 (Box 21)
  - Liggett & Myers--Inside Liggett Group, 1976-1977 (Box 17)
  - Liggett & Myers--L&M direct mail, 2011-2015; 2 folders (Box 17)
  - Liggett & Myers--Manufacturing Plants and Offices, 1921 (Box 17)
  - Liggett & Myers--Marketing Dimensions, 1968 (Box 17)
  - Liggett & Myers--Official Political and Other Valuable Information, 1892-1920 (Box 17)
  - Liggett & Myers--Reprinted articles, 1896-1973 (Box 17)
  - Liggett & Myers--Retailer Educational Program: Consumer Communications for Retailers, 1972 (Box 17)
  - Liggett & Myers--Retailer Educational Program: Retail Management, 1970 (Box 17)
  - Liggett & Myers--Salesman receipt book, 1930s (Box 17)
  - Liggett & Myers--Selling Dimensions, 1977 (Box 17)
  - Liggett & Myers--Some Facts About the Liggett & Myers Tobacco Company, undated (Box 17)
  - Liggett & Myers--Sports Records and Street Guide (Olympics Summer Games), 1984 (Box 17)
  - Liggett & Myers--The Book of Presidents, 1932 (Box 17)
  - Liggett & Myers--The Making of Cigarettes, 1922 (Box 17)
  - Liggett & Myers--Tobacco News, 1975-1976 (Box 17)
  - Liggett & Myers--Tobaccoland USA, 1943 (Box 21)
  - Liggett & Myers--Velvet Joe's Almanac, 1922 (Box 17)
  - Liggett & Myers--Webster's Dictionary free gift with carton purchase, 1970s (Box 17)
  - Liggett & Myers/Chesterfield--Thoroughbreds, undated (Box 17)
  - Liggett & Myers/Vector Group--Press release on nicotine-free cigarette, 2002 (Box 17)
  - Lois Mattox Miller (Reader's Digest)--Lung Cancer and Cigarettes: The Latest Findings, 1962 (Box 17)
  - Lois Mattox Miller and James Monahan (Reader's Digest)--The Cigarette Industry Changes Its Mind, 1958 (Box 17)
  - Lois Mattox Miller and James Monahan (Reader's Digest)--The Facts Behind Filter-Tip Cigarettes, 1957 (Box 17)
  - Lois Mattox Miller and James Monahan (Reader's Digest)--The Search for "Safer" Cigarettes, 1959 (Box 17)
  - Lorillard--Lorillard and Tobacco, 1977 (Box 17)
  - Loyd--Producing Lighted Cigarettes (parlor tricks), 1936 (Box 17)
  - Marlboro--Chili Roundup Recipe Book, 2002 (Box 17)
  - Marlboro--Direct mail, 2002-2003 (Box 17)
  - Marlboro--Direct mail, Country Cooking, 1996-1998 (Box 17)
  - Marlboro--Direct mail, Menthol, 1996-2012 (Box 17)
  - Marlboro--Direct mail, Unlimited campaign, 1995-1998 (Box 17)
  - Marlboro--Timeline and obituaries of Marlboro Men actors, 1987-2014 (Box 17)
  - Marlboro--Unlimited Premier Issue, 1996 (Box 21)
  - Mayo Clinic--Articles on Charles Mayo's scepticism over tobacco-cancer link, 1955-1976 (Box 17)
  - Merit--Awards catalog, 1997 (Box 17)
  - NASCAR--Winston Cup Series media guides, 1985-2000; 3 folders (Box 17)
  - National Cancer Institute--The Role of the Media in Promoting and Reducing Tobacco Use, 2008; 2 folders (Box 17)
  - National Cancer Institute--Women, Tobacco and Cancer, 2004 (Box 17)
  - Natural American Spirit--Direct mail, 2001 (Box 17)
  - Nicotine Alkaloid Control Plate--Correspondence, photographs and Nuclear Regulatory Commission technical opinions, 1982-1985, 2019 (Box 17)
  - NIH (National Institute of Health)/National Cancer Institute--"Light" Cigarettes and Cancer Risk, 2010 (Box 17)
  - Official Indy Lights Championship Yearbook, 1997 (Box 19)
  - OLTS (On the Lighter Side: newsletter for lighter collectors), 1995-1997 (Box 17)
  - Philip Morris--Article on Apollo/Soyuz commemorative cigarette pack, 2014 (Box 17)
  - Philip Morris--Direct mail, 1996-1999 (Box 17)
  - Philip Morris--Philip Morris Magazine, 1987-1989; 2 folders (Box 17)
  - Philip Morris--Youth smoking prevention, 2000-2008 (Box 17)
  - Picadilly (U.K.)--"Stubbed Out" article with example of advertisements, 2016 (Box 18)
  - Pocket Lighter Preservation Guild and Historic Society printout, 2017 (Box 18)
  - Powder Puffs (cosmetic compacts collectibles) newsletter, 1995-1996 (Box 18)
  - Research files--E-cigarettes, 2013-2014 (Box 18)
  - Research files--Marketing to women, 1988-2008 (Box 18)
  - Research files--Ronson cigarette cases, 1932-1995 (Box 18)
  - Research files--Smoking in the movies, 1997-2014 (Box 18)
  - Research files--Sports and special events marketing, 1970-2014 (Box 18)
  - Research files--Tobacco industry response to smoking controversy, 1954-2014 (Box 18)
  - Richard Corliss (Time)--Chuff Chuff Puff Puff (Marlboro Unlimited train), 1996 (Box 18)
  - R.J. Reynolds--Annual report, 1964 (Box 18)
  - R.J. Reynolds--Cigarette Ordering Book (Joe Camel on cover), 1991 (Box 21)
  - R.J. Reynolds--Direct mail, 2001 (Box 18)
  - R.J. Reynolds--E-mail, 2002-2003 (Box 18)
  - R.J. Reynolds--Our 100th Anniversary 1875-1975 (Box 19)
  - R.J. Reynolds/Camel--Know Your Nerves, 1934 (Box 18)
  - Robert Littell (Reader's Digest)--Cigarette Holders Put to the Test, 1999 (Box 18)
  - Robert Tefertillar (Antiques and Collecting)--The Overlooked Collectible (vintage ads), 1999 (Box 18)
  - Robert Wood Johnson Foundation--The Way We Were: Tobacco Ads Through the Ages, 2011 (Box 18)
  - Rod Taylor--Article on Red Man chewing tobacco tin collecting (Pinkerton Tobacco), 2005 (Box 18)
  - Roxanne Palmer--Cigarette Companies Sidestep "Light" Ban with Colored Packaging: A Long History of Deception, 2013 (Box 18)
  - Salem--Direct mail, 1996-2007 (Box 18)
  - Salem--Direct mail, 50th anniversary, 2005-2006 (Box 18)
  - Sam Blum (Harper's magazine)--An Ode to the Cigarette Code, 1986 (Box 18)
  - The Sentinel--Printouts from keyword searches for cigarettes and Murad brand, 1923-1939; 3 folders (Box 18)
  - Sheet music--[Chesterfield] Baseball (America's Favorite Game); Tom Waring, Paul Gibbons, Craig Leitch, 1939 (Box 19)
  - Sheet music--[Chesterfield] Smoke Dreams; Lloyd Shaffer, John Klenner, Ted Steele, 1947 (Box 19)
  - Sheet music--Story of Two Cigarettes; Mickey Stoner, Fred Jay and Leonard Marker; Paul Weirick arrangement, 1945 (Box 21)
  - Sheet music--The Man from the South (With a Big Cigar in His Mouth); Rube Bloom, Harry Woods, 1930 (Box 19)
  - Smoking Surveys--Direct mail, 1997-2000 (Box 18)
  - Southern Israelite--Reprinted pages with tobacco content, 1937-1966 (Box 18)
  - Speedway Motorsports annual report, 1998 (Box 18)
  - Stanley Frank (True magazine)--To Smoke or Not to Smoke: That Is Still the Question, 1968 (Box 18)
  - Sterling Remedy Company--Don't Tobacco Spit and Smoke Your Life Away: Take No-To-Bac, 1895 (Box 18)
  - Stock certificates, 1911-1990 (Box 19)
    Includes: American Tobacco (1967); Continental Tobacco (1969); Liggett & Myers (1950); Lorillard (1911); RJR Nabisco (1990); Tobacco Products Corporation (1929)
  - Tobacco Institute--North Carolina and Tobacco, 1975 (Box 18)
  - Tobacco Institute--North Carolina's Tobacco Heritage, undated (Box 18)
  - Tobacco Institute--Science and Smoke, 1979 (Box 18)
  - Tobacco Institute--Tobacco: Deeply Rooted in America's Heritage, undated (Box 18)
  - Tobacco Institute--Tobacco: Pioneer in American Industry, 1975 (Box 18)
  - Tobacco Institute--Tobacco Industry Profile, 1979 (Box 18)
  - Tobacco Institute--Virginia's Tobacco Heritage, undated (Box 18)
  - Tobacco labels (Scotten, Dillon Company of Detroit, Mich.), undated; 7 folders (Box 19)
    Includes: Dan Patch Cut Plug; Landmark Cut Plug; Laredo Cut Plug; Long Distance; Oceanic Cut Plug; Pep Blended Cigarette Tobacco; Ramrod Cigarette Tobacco
  - Tom Robbins--Still Life with Woodpecker, 1980 (Box 18)
  - USA Gold--Direct mail, 2009-2014 (Box 18)
  - Vikki Conwell (Atlanta Journal-Constitution)--"Chippers" Smoke Less, to Fight Stress, 2009 (Oversize-folder 1)
  - Virginia Slims--Catalogs, 1994-2001 (Box 18)
  - Virginia Slims--Direct mail, 1996-2000 (Box 18)
  - Virginia Slims--Tennis Championship Series, 1986 (Box 18)
  - Weekly Standard--Dennis Prager: The Anti-Tobacco Crusade; John Calfee: Why the War on Smoking Will Fail, 1998 (Box 18)
  - Wendy Bounds (Wall Street Journal)--Don't Throw Out That Old Ashtray Yet, 1997 (Box 21)
  - Wes Raynal (Autoweek)--Butt Out (tobacco sponsorship of racing), 1994 (Box 18)
  - Winchester Little Cigars--Football Guide, 1996 (Box 18)
  - Winston--NASCAR, 1998-2001 (Box 18)
  - Winston--No Bull/No Boundaries sweepstakes, 2000 (Box 18)
  - Winston--Winston Cup Series bumper sticker, 1988 (Box 18)
  - Winston Cup Illustrated, 1995-1996; 2 folders (Box 18)
  - Wisconsin State Journal--Tobacco-related cartoons, 1997 (Box 18)
  - Yesteryear--Joe Camel Remains Collectors' Staple, 1997 (Box 21)
  - Zippo (lighter)--Lighter collector guide, 1994 (Box 18)
  - Zippo (lighter)--Motor Sports Racing Guide, 1997 (Box 18)
- Audiovisual Materials, 1992-2012 and undated; 5
  - Winston Holiday Music volume 1, 1992 (Box AV1, Audio-cassette RL-11677-CAS-001)
  - Winston Holiday Music volume 2, 1992 (Box AV1, Audio-cassette RL-11677-CAS-002)
  - Cigarette Commercials from the 50s and 60s (DVD), 2010 (Box AV1, Optical-disc RL-11677-OP-001)
  - Got a Light, Mac? Vintage Songs about Smoking 1926-1954 (CD), 2007 (Box AV1, Optical-disc RL-11677-OP-002)
  - Report of the Surgeon General--Health Consequences of Involuntary Exposure fo Tobacco Smoke (CD), 2006 (Box AV1, Optical-disc RL-11677-OP-003)
  - Report of the Surgeon General--Health Consequences of Smoking on the Human Body (CD), 2004 (Box AV1, Optical-disc RL-11677-OP-004)
  - Report of the Surgeon General--How Tobacco Smoke Causes Disease (CD), 2010 (Box AV1, Optical-disc RL-11677-OP-005)
  - Report of the Surgeon General--Preventing Tobacco Use Among Youth and Young Adults (CD), 2012 (Box AV1, Optical-disc RL-11677-OP-006)
  - Scene Smoking: Cigarettes, Cinema and the Myth of Cool (DVD), undated (Box AV1, Optical-disc RL-11677-OP-007)
  - Secrets Through the Smoke (Dr. Jeffrey Wigand) (DVD), undated (Box AV1, Optical-disc RL-11677-OP-008)
  - Smoke Screeners: An educational program to help young people decode smoking in the movies (DVD), 1999 (Box AV1, Optical-disc RL-11677-OP-009)
  - Smokin': Classic Cigarette Commercials, a Look Back at the 50s and 60s (DVD), 2011 (Box AV1, Optical-disc RL-11677-OP-010)
  - Winston Cup Series--Kick in the Asphalt (CD), 1997 (Box AV1, Optical-disc RL-11677-OP-011)
  - Marlboro Unlimited The Train The Trip The Gear, 1995 (Box AV1, Video-cassette RL-11677-VHS-001)
  - Winston Cup Official Thunder Theater Video, 1997 (Box AV1, Video-cassette RL-11677-VHS-002)